Chris Hutchison

Web Developer

chris88@gmail.com 404-771-1782 1012 Druid Hills Reserve Dr Atlanta,. GA 30329 linkedin.com/in/chrishutchison88 http://github.com/chrishutchison9

A highly motivated web developer with the ability to deliver outstanding work, understanding the needs of clients while meeting proposed deadlines in an efficient manner. To continue to advance my career within an outstanding corporation where I will be able to utilize my skills, experience and creativity.

Work History

Omnitec June 2017 - Present

Web Developer

3845 Pleasantdale Road, Atlanta, GA 30340

• Contracted to do website development on DVIDS properties including DefenseTV(http://defensetv.com) and DVIDSHub(http://dvidshub.net)

Codesigned Aug 2015 - Feb 2017

Front End Web Developer

2970 Clairmont Rd #940, Atlanta, GA 30329

- Developed web parts, features, workflows, for SharePoint 2013 using the SharePoint Client Site Object Model and Server Side Object Model
- Develop client side code for web applications using HTML, jQuery, JavaScript, CSS, and other technologies
- Leveraged web services to access data from other systems
- Code public facing website and landing pages for flagship product on Hubspot platform.

Pursuant Health (formerly Solohealth)

Nov 2014 - May 2015

Software Developer

780 Johnson Ferry Rd NE #625, Atlanta, GA 30342

Building new functionality for both a front-facing Kiosk system/network and back-end systems and websites.

- Develop, install, debug and test complex systems.
- Building web-based applications using PHP, MySQL, Linux and Apache.
- Used technologies including jQuery, AngularJS, and GIT.

SteelPivot, Inc. Mar 2014 - Oct 2014

Web Application Developer

225 Peachtree St NW #1985, Atlanta, GA 30303

As a Web Application Developer, I actively contributed through planning, testing, and implementation of web-based applications using LAMP stack.

- Development, test, debug, and maintain web-based applications in Agile development environment.
- Migration of 1000+ websites to new infrastructure with minimal downtime.
- Work with clients to create, migrate, deploy and manage systems and sites.
- Integrate existing PHP applications and websites with SugarCRM.
- Customize SugarCRM core to add additional logic.
- Manage internal websites, servers and databases.
- Architect databases for variety of web applications and systems.
- Architected and managed SQL and NoSQL database servers for a variety of web applications and systems.
- Use AngularJS and jQuery to develop a dynamic pricing calculator with sliding controls.
- Designed and taught hands-on classes on topics such as advanced Apache concepts (working with SSL and protected web directories)
- Use PHP, MongoDB, and MySQL to develop systems and automate tasks.
- Design and code landing pages for thenetworkcloud.com and steelpivot.com using technologies including Bootstrap, Photoshop, Wordpress, PHP, and jQuery.

Greenlight Print / Khraze

Web Application Developer

1455 Oakbrook Dr #900 Norcross, GA 30093

Develop multiple scheduling applications (front-end for clients and backend for administrators using advanced technologies including jqGrid). Application features included interfacing with Nexmo SMS Api and jQuery UI Calendar. Technologies used include Codeigniter PHP Framework, jQuery, HTML5 Hashbang navigation through using PathJS.

- Code website for leading helmet protection gear (Guardian Caps) and buildout of store and forums. Themed osCommerce to fit main site style and customized osCommerce frontend and customer input fields to client demands.
- Code company website (khraze.com) with advanced forms and interactive features including a portfolio slideshow.
- Customized dixiegentlemen.com to client's specifications. Store used OpenCart PHP software.
- Helped code custom application and buildout of TheExpressionary.com to integrate with social login for customers (with Facebook, Google, etc.) and theming a custom video player to fit design. Site coded in Zend Framework.

Sep 2012 - Dec 2013

Vehicle Media Jun 2010 - Jul 2011

Web Developer

887 West Marietta St NW, Atlanta, GA 30318

• Developed websites using PHP and MySQL from psd files for companies in the fashion and roofing industry.

• Developed custom wordpress plugin (https://wordpress.org/plugins/online-outbox-subscription-form/) for OnlineOutbox.com to allow users to connect to their account and use a widget shortcode inserted on their site to allow users to subscribe to a newsletter.

Alphanet CS Aug 2008 - Jan 2010

Web Developer Los Angeles, CA

- Coded sites using PHP and MySQL for a textile plant (Princess Paper) as well as theme design to fit logo.
- Code one page checkout redesign of the checkout page in Magento showing all sections(payment, shipping, customer details) at once instead of the default of the sections being hidden and completed sequentially.
- Developed and streamlined a network of directory sites that allow users to find local professionals including florists, dentists, and beauty salons.

Education

Georgia State University - Perimeter College 555 N Indian Creek Dr Clarkston, GA 30021

Computer Science Associates Program, Degree in progress, Expected Graduation 2020 Atlanta, GA